# **Bee-jay Paiz**

#### **PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY**

Former educator transitioning to a career in web development. Self-taught programmer using free online resources. Proven track record in previous positions as a reliable and committed team member. Experience with collaborating in a diverse, international workplace, adhering to strict deadlines, and presenting complex ideas to a variety of audiences.

### PROJECTS @ github.com/beejathon

### <u>notbadreads</u> | JavaScript, React, React-Router, Firebase, Tailwind

A goodreads clone where users can search a database of books, organize a personal library, write reviews and interact with other users

- Front-end built with React and React Router; styled with Tailwind CSS
- Leverages Google Books API to fetch book data
- Utilizes Firestore to persist user data (personal library, user update feed, reviews, comments, likes)

# Where The Waldos At? | JavaScript, React, Firebase

A photo-tagging app that functions as a game based on the popular series of children's puzzle books

- Front-end built using React, React Hooks, and the React-Menu library to manage the game's state and UI
- Leverages Firestore to store game data and keep track of high scores

# The Croc Pit | Javascript, React, React-Router, Material UI

A mock e-commerce web page for Croc shoes

- Front-end focused single-page-application built using React and React-Router
- Utilizes The Sneaker Database API to fetch and dynamically display products

### Battleship | Javascript, Jest, Webpack

A web browser game based on the popular board game

- Built with Test-Driven-Development as a focus
- Created unit tests using Jest before writing the core functions of the game

# To-do List | Javascript, Webpack, Firebase

A simple web app to create and track projects and tasks

- Developed with focus on OOP and SOLID principles, keeping application logic separate from display/UI
- Refactored to integrate Firebase services, allowing users to sign in using Google Authentication and persist their data using Firestore backend-as-a-service

#### CONTACT

#### Location:

1/2 11 Glenspean Street, Glasgow G43 2YZ

#### Mobile:

+44 7919510538

#### E-mail:

bipaiz@gmail.com

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

### Languages:

JavaScript, HTML, CSS

#### Libraries / Services:

React, React Hooks, React-Router, Firebase, Material UI, Tailwind

#### Dev Tools / Runtimes:

Git, Jest, Webpack, CLI, npm

# EDUCATION & TRAINING

TESOL Certification Coventry House International OnTESOL November 2014

# Bachelor of Arts in English

San Francisco State University September 2010 - July 2012

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# Warehouse Operative | Unineed | Glasgow, UK February 2022 - Present

- Receive merchandise and organize warehouse inventory
- Pick and pack customer orders

# ESL/Math Teacher | Edison School | Hanoi, Vietnam

August 2018 - March 2021

- Instructed classes in ESL, Algebra I, Geometry, and Algebra II for secondary and high-school students
- Provided ongoing assessment and feedback on student performance and communicated issues with both support staff and parents
- Collaborated with a diverse group of teachers and students to plan and facilitate extracurricular games and performances for events

### SAT Instructor | International English Education | Hanoi, Vietnam September 2017 - August 2018

- Instructed classes in SAT and IELTS Preparation for secondary and high-school students
- Helped students achieve desired benchmarks

# ESL Teacher | Wellspring International School | Hanoi, Vietnam August 2015 - June 2017

- Instructed classes in ESL, Academic Reading, Academic Writing, SAT and IELTS Preparation
- Maintained dialogue with management and parents regarding student behavior and performance

### Volunteer Tutor | Reading Partners | San Leandro CA, USA October 2013 - May 2015

• Tutored disadvantaged students to improve general English language fluency and close their reading level gap with their peers

# Warehouse Operative | Kirin Hobby | Hayward CA, USA January 2013 - May 2015

Cashier | Marshalls Department Stores | San Bruno CA, USA February 2012 - August 2012

Social Media Intern | Bindlestiff Studio | San Francisco CA, USA February 2012 - July 2012

Stocker/Cashier | PetSmart | San Leandro CA, USA August 2008 - May 2011